

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Application

Development, Project Management, Architectural Design, Business Intelligence, Tibco

Spotfire, Requirement Gathering, Unit

Testing, Confluence, Qlik View, Tableau, Docker, Oracle, JIRA, SQL



Current Designation: Principal Software Engineer Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: RxLogix Corporation Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Application Development, Project Management, Quality Management, Architectural Design, Business Intelligence, Requirement Gathering, Unit

Testing, Confluence, Qlik View, Tableau, Docker, Oracle, JIRA, SQL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Experience Summary:

I have 8 years 10 Months of Business Intelligence experience in the field of Life sciences domain.

I have more than 6 Years of strong experience in Tibco Spotfire tool in creating dashboard and different kind of visualization in reports.

I have been involved in requirement gathering, report design, report development, unit testing and code deployment using Tibco Spotfire server, Spotfire Webplayer and IBM Cognos suite.

Worked on Spotfire server architecture designing and setting up the spotfire server for reporting solutions for customer like FDA, Merck, Celgene, Novartis

Finding out the RCA, Solutions for the issues and handling client communication.

Designed new reports and dashboard for pharmacovigilance reporting and signaling solutions with different kind of KPIs Created Linear Regression model in spotfire

Experience with S3 bucket, Github, Conflucne, Jira for code management and documents

Work Experience

RxLogix Corporation as Principal Software Engineer

Aug 2016 to Till Date

Designing the spotfire model for new projects

Interacting with Business users and Stakeholders for requirement gathering documents.

Providing Estimates from end to end for application development in projects.

Developed complex spotfire reports using Information link, Excel data, Parametrized information link, Personalized information link, data on demand, marking, document property, Drill-through visualization, tags, lists, Multiple Filtering Scheme, Iron python and R function

Involved in design & finalization security implementation, providing the solution for multiple country implementations Spotfire setup Implementation via Docker, Spotfire setup with Scripting to create UI based installer

Worked in Agile software development and Waterfall Model methodology

Successfully handled a team of 4-5 team member, Carried out communications with client & cascaded it to team members.

Training and mentoring the newly joined resources

Client Merck, Johnson and Johnson, CSL, Alexion, Novartis,,FDA,Merck,Novartis,Celgene

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=2670edf0750469ead654b70313f5540f0b5f0050481b00165645105f090...

Data Oracle, JSON, flat files,Excel files
Data sources Argus,ArisG,Faers
Tools Spotfire 6.5,7.8,7.11,10.3

Role Report Developer and Tibco Spotfire SME

Period August 2016 to Present

Project Description: PV Reports is the total One-Stop Integrated PV Reporting and Analytics Solution

PV Reports is the most advanced, user-friendly, and self-service tool for Regulatory Reports, Ad-HOC Reports, OOB Spotfire Integration and Visualizations.

Also worked on the PV signal project to generate reports to find out the signal and related data. These are the dashboard which refresh at a particular interval to refresh the data. Also tell the user about productivity and compliance of user based out of his work done and time taken.

Creating the new report & Dashboard based on user requirement in Spotfire.

Integrate report with iframe based product

Provide access on spotfire library and managing User

Run report with the help of Automation service job builder

Writing Installation Qualification for spotfire setup and code deployment

Upgrade project of spotfire from lower version to higher version

Cognizant as Associate

Dec 2011 to Aug 2016

Databases Oracle Tools Spotfire 7.0 Role Developer

Period October 2015 to August 2016

Project Description: This project caters the need of Asian country sales data for Merck medicine. Here data source is Oracle and reporting is done using Spotfire.

Role and Responsibilities

Creating the new report & Dashboard based on new requirement in Spotfire.

Made changes in already present dashboard

Provide access on spotfire library

Changing schema from Dev to test & Test to production

Project #3

Client Merck
Databases Oracle, Argus

Tools Spotfire, Cognos 10 Report Studio, Event Studio

Role Developer

Period July 2013 to September 2015

Project Description: This BI project was to cater the need of Reporting for countries US for Human Health. Here data source is Argus database and with the help of oracle reporting is done using Spotfire and IBM Cognos Report Studio.

Role and Responsibilities

Creating the new report &Dashboard based on new requirement in Spotfire.

Involved in enhancing the report in spotfire

Creating online reports in report studio and scheduling Job through event studio

Supporting execution in report failure or job scheduling

Project #4

Project Name AH MDM EEA

Client Merck
Databases Excel File
Tools Spotfire

Role Developer

Period June 2013 to July 2013

Project Description: This project was to cater the need of Reporting for countries US for animal Health. Here source data was coming from an Excel file and reporting is done using spotfire. Duplicate data is removed by strategic decisions from Master file using HIN error file.

Role and Responsibilities

Understanding requirement for design of project and designing report in spotfire.

Project #5

Client Merck

Operating System Windows 7.

Tools Cognos Framework Manager, SQL developer, Cognos business intelligence, and Cognos business intelligence advanced Role

Role Developer

Period Jan 2013 to May 2013

Project Description: The Merck DW S&A Emerging Mkt PH 2 project is to design & build the Ad hoc Package.

Role and Responsibilities

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=2670edf0750469ead654b70313f5540f0b5f0050481b00165645105f090...

Understanding requirement for design of project Adhoc Package Design and Development Design & execution of Unit test cases. Project #6

Client Merck

Tools Cognos Report Studio 8 & 10, SQL developer

Role Developer

Period September2012 -Dec 2012

Project Description: The project was aimed to develop sales reports and ad hoc Package for Israel.

Role and Responsibilities

Reports Design and Development

Reports Unit testing.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Guru Jambheshwar University of Science and Technology (GJUST), Hisar in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

IBM report studio author

IT Skills

	Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
	QlikView, Tableau, Python, Oracle			
	Windows, Linux server, AWS			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time